<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Aidan Harris - Meta</title><link href="https://aidanharr.is/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://aidanharr.is/feeds/meta.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://aidanharr.is/</id><updated>2015-05-24T22:37:00+01:00</updated><entry><title> Hello World</title><link href="https://aidanharr.is/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-24T22:37:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-05-24T22:37:00+01:00</updated><author><name>aidanharris</name></author><id>tag:aidanharr.is,2015-05-24:/hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've meant to create this website for a while now but haven't had the
time necessary to set the website up. I snapped up the snarky .io domain
name favoured by developers and startups a while a go and today, or
rather tonight, I've finally dedicated the time necessary to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've meant to create this website for a while now but haven't had the
time necessary to set the website up. I snapped up the snarky .io domain
name favoured by developers and startups a while a go and today, or
rather tonight, I've finally dedicated the time necessary to setting
this site up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly it did take a lot longer than I'd anticipated and there were
several roadblocks such as forgetting to alter the firewall settings to
allow HTTPS traffic and then spending the next half hour wondering why
everything's broken (a rookie mistake I'll be sure to avoid in the
future).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above is an interesting answer to the following question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
What is the purpose of this website?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's many websites on the Internet that all fulfil many purposes.
This site is relatively small hosted on a small VPS in London provided
via &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=a285f2bc1129"&gt;Digital
Ocean&lt;/a&gt;. The main
purpose of this site is to document my journey as a developer. I will be
writing about the various programming languages I decide to learn and
the tools I use. I want this site to essentially serve as a portfolio of
my knowledge and skills and allow me to use it as a reference.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>